Guide to the Gordon Quan papers, 1982-2012 MS 618
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Gordon Quan papers
1982-2012
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Gordon Quan
MS 618
4 Linear Feet (3 boxes plus digital content)
This collection consists of business papers, articles, photographs, and awards created by or about Gordon Quan, immigration lawyer and former Houston City Council member. Also included are articles and items about the Houston community in general and the Houston Asian American community specifically.
Biographical Note
Gordon Quan was born in China, though he became an American citizen at birth due to his father being a U.S. servicemember. The Quan family moved to Houston following the Chinese Revolution in 1951. Quan received a degree in History and Government from the University of Texas at Austin. He then returned to Houston, where he taught at E.O. Smith Junior High School, and earned a Master's Degree in Education from the University of Houston and a law degree from the South Texas College of Law.
Quan founded his immigration firm, Quan, Burdette & Perez PC, in early 1980. In 1999, Quan became the first Asian American to be elected into the Houston City Council in an at large position. In 2001, he was selected by Mayor Lee. P. Brown and the City Council to serve as Mayor Pro-Tem. Quan has also served as president of the board of directors of the Asian Pacific American Municipal Officials organization and held many other positions in various charities and committees throughout Houston. After ending his term on the City Council, Quan returned to practicing law at his firm, which merged with Tindall & Foster PC in 2007 to become Foster Quan LLP.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains papers generated by Quan's political career, as well as papers and newspaper clippings relating to his work with local charities and committees. Also included are various memorabilia, items relating to the local Houston Asian American communities and a variety of awards received by Quan.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was donated to Rice University by Gordon Quan, via Dr. Anne Chao and the Chao Center for Asian Studies, Rice University.
Index Terms
Subjects
Chinese Americans; Politics and government; Political culture; Asian Americans
Document Types
photographs; letters (correspondence); awards; clippings (information artifacts); programs (documents)
Places
Texas--Houston
- Series I: Personal Papers, 1999-2005; 180123
  - Campaign Materials, 2003-2004, n.d.; 180126 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Certificates, 2003-2004; 180127 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - City Council Papers, 2002, n.d.; 180128 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2001; 180129 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Criminal Alien Removal Act, 2003; 180130 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Land Assembly and Redevelopment Authority, 2003-2004; 180131 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - National League of Cities Panel Meeting, 2004; 180132 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Newsletters, 2000-2004; 180133 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Photographs, 1999-2005, n.d.; 180144 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Programs, 2000-2004; 180135 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Tranparencies, 2002; 180134 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Series II: Newspaper Articles, 1999-2012; 180124
  - Asian American Community Clippings, 2000-2004, n.d.; 180136 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - General Community Clippings, 2000-2005, n.d.; 180137 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Incomplete Clippings, 1999, n.d.; 180138 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Non-English Clippings, 2000-2003, nd.; 180139 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Political Clippings, 1999-2006, n.d.; 180140 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Gordon Quan Clippings, 1999-2012, n.d.; 180141 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Series III: Awards and ephemera, 1982-2008; 180125
  - Chinese Americans Past and Present Workbook, 1982; 180142 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Committee of 100 Survey, 2001; 180143 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Asian American Legacy Awards (CD-ROM), 2008; 180145 (Box 1, Disc 1)
  - Channel 17 Houston Media Source live show pictures (CD-ROM), 2005; 180175 (Box 1, Disc 2)
  - The Connection: Affordable Housing (#405) VHS, 2005; 180173 (Box 1)
  - Gordon Quan for County Judge shirt, n.d.; 180150 (Box 1)
  - Thai Alliance in America Spirit of Leadership award, 2005; 180151 (Box 1)
  - US Census Bureau - ACS: Real People, Real Issues (#V01-249) VHS, 2001; 180174 (Box 1)
  - Youth Cultural Exchange Project t-shirt, n.d.; 180148 (Box 1)
  - Youth Cultural Exchange Project t-shirt, n.d.; 180149 (Box 1)
  - Youth Leadership Council Community Leader Award, 2002; 180152 (Box 1)
  - Alpha Phi Omega 5th Biennal Convention Guest Speaker Plaque, 2000; 180153 (Box 2)
  - APAMO Appreciation Award, 2004; 180161 (Box 2)
  - Asian Chamber of Commerce Achievement Award, 2006; 180159 (Box 2)
  - CANO/CARECEN plaque, 2001; 180160 (Box 2)
  - Chinese American Citizens Alliance 50th Anniversary Gala award, 2004; 180163 (Box 2)
  - Congresswoman Barbara Jordan Legacy Award, 2004; 180162 (Box 2)
  - Filipino American Council of South Texas Friends of Filipinos Award, 2004; 180156 (Box 2)
  - Houston Asian Junior Chamber of Commerce Award, 2001; 180165 (Box 2)
  - Institute for the Development and Education of Asian American Leader award, 2005; 180164 (Box 2)
  - Mayor's Youth Council award, 2001; 180155 (Box 2)
  - MHMRA Culture Bridges Award, 2003; 180154 (Box 2)
  - Orchestra award, 2003; 180166 (Box 2)
  - Philippine-American Chamber of Commerce Plaque, 2002; 180158 (Box 2)
  - YMCA Grand Club Plaque, 180157 (Box 2)
- Series IV: Oversize Materials, 2002-2005; 180167
  - Asian Heritage Day display board, n.d.; 180172 (Box 3)
  - Proclamation, 2002; 180171 (Box 3)
  - Resolution, 2005; 180170 (Box 3)
  - Transparencies, 2002; 180169 (Box 3)
  - Youth Cultural Exchange Project, 2003; 180168 (Box 3)